Yan Dai

PERSONAL DATA

DATE OF BIRTH: 27 December 1989 VISA STATUS: Resident Visa

ADDRESS: 5 Fairview Crescent, Kelburn, Wellington, New Zeland

PHONE: 021 023 82956

EMAIL: alvindaiyan@gmail.com
GITHUB: https://github.com/alvindaiyan

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I have over 3 years' experience in building enterprise and web based application. I am hard working, reliable and keen to work in a forward thinking team. I am creative, independent and a good communicator with a desire to acquire new skills as well as advance existing skills.

My aim is to work as a full stack software developer, eventually having responsibilities in software architecture, business analysis and project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SKILL DESCRIPTION	Experience	LEVEL
Programming Skill		
Java (J2SE, J2EE)	Paid	Advance
Unix/Linux	Practical	Intermediate
Go	Practical	Intermediate
Android Development	Practical	Intermediate
C#	Paid	Intermediate
AngularJS	Practical	Basic
DATABASE PROGRAMMING		
SQL Server	Practical	Intermediate
MySql	Practical	Intermediate
PostgreSql	Paid	Intermediate
Cassandra	Paid	Intermediate
WEB DEVELOPMENT		
JSP	Paid	Advance
SpringMVC, JAX-RS	Paid	Intermediate
HTML & CSS	Paid	Intermediate
Javascript & JQuery	Paid	Intermediate
PROJECT MANAGEMENT		
Agile Methodology	Practical	Intermediate

EDUCATION

2009-2013 Bachelor of Engineering (Hons) in Sofware Engineering,

Victoria University of Wellington, Wellington

Honours Project: "PSO for Feature Construction and Binary Classification"

Published Paper: New Representations in PSO for Feature Construction in Classification

Advisor: Prof. Mengjie ZHANG

2008-2009 Certificates in English Proficiency and Foundation Studies

Victoria University of Wellington, Wellington

WORK EXPERIENCE

NOV 2013-CURRENT

Software Engineer at SYL RESEARCH LTD., Wellington

Enterprise Search Engine Using Java (SYL Platform 2.0, 2.1 and 2.5)

Developed new Java crawler for IBM LotusNotes, and used commercially. Optimised the Java crawler for IBM LotusNotes to double the performance.

Developed a module (Java, Apache POI) for extracting embedded documents from MS Word, Excel and Powerpoint. This is used by syl 2.1, and syl 2.5 platform.

Main Developer for WordPerfect Document parsing function and used by syl 2.1 and syl 2.5 platform.

Developed a RESTful API (JAX-RS using Jersey) for metadata services in syl 2.1 and syl 2.5 platform.

Designed and Developed a responsive web based User Interface prototype using HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap.

JUNE 2015-CURRENT

FreeLancer Developer at Profile Guru, Wellington A Semantic Based Job Hunting Website and Web Services

Implemented Restful API and business logic in Java with Spring Framework. Improved the test process of the application with unit test. Lead and Developed the front-end tier with AngularJS, Yeoman, HTML5 and CSS3.

MAR 2015-JULY 2015

FreeLancer Android Developer at YIMIN, Wellington A Immigration Helper Application

Using Android Studio, Butter knife and Dagger for application developement.

JAN 2011-FEB 2012

Software Engineer at Beijing ShenZhou Aerospace Software Technology Co., Ltd, Beijing, China

Knowledge based engineering management project for China Aerospace Science \mathcal{E} Industry Corp (CASIC)

Help with requirements analysis for the functions of knowledge acquisition, assessment of the problem, revision and evaluation system.

Implemented the online document viewing system which convert the MS document to Adobe Flash by Java & Linux Command-line.

Research on the related algorithm such as the Genetic Programming, Support Vector Machine, Bayesian Network for data mining, search engine and Auto error detection

Implemented research model in Java and eventually used in production environment. Research on Java implementation plan for using Al algorithms (Genetic algorithm) to achieve a particular objective.

JAN 2013-MAR 2013

Software Engineer (Summer Intern) at FRONDE SYSTEMS GROUP, Wellington

Auto Billing Reporting System in Java

Requirements analysis for understanding the complex charging rules and implementing these complex rules.

Software Architecture design: designing the basic structure of the system, helping with deciding the programming language and demonstrating the software architecture to the stakeholder.

Software Design: using UML to design the software, interface design and demonstrating the software design to the stakeholder. $\label{eq:control}$

Team Management as a Scrum Master for our agile methodology.

AUG 2013-JAN 2014

Software Developer (Part-time) at PRICETECH, Wellington Web Based Applications Using .Net

Maitenance of existing Pricetech Client Applications.

Software developement using C# and ASP.Net for the web-based price application. Software requirements gathering, including meeting clients, software requirements design.

Nov 2012-FEB 2013

Research Assistant at Victoria University of Wellington, Wellington Evolutionary Computation for Data Manipulation and Using Particle Swarm Optimisation (PSO) for Feature Construction

Published Paper: *PSO for Feature Construction and Binary Classification*Research and Design on the related algorithm for feature construction using PSO which is one of the very first research in this area.

Implementing the designed algorithm in Java and Recording and analysing the experiment results.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Honours Degree of Engineering in Software Engineering and Achieving a B+ average for all past four years courses.

Have published two papers for Genetic and Evolutionary Computation Conference (GECCO) 13 and EvoApps 2014.

Have developed a service-based, open-sourced instant messaging application using spare time, this project is hosted on github.

Volunteer Software Engineer at Habitat for Humanity to help with their content management system.

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Technology, Reading, Programming

Have been learning and playing the accordion for nine years.

Writing technical blogs, you can find my blog at http://alvindaiyan.github.io/

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Fluent

CHINESE: Mother tongue

REFEREES

Peter De Vocht

Founder & Chief Scientist

Syl Semantics

Phone: +64 (21) 0215 2225 Email: peter@peter.co.nz

Address: Level 1, Featherston Tower, 23 Waring Taylor Street, Welling-

ton, 6145 New Zealand

Wei Ren

Technical Project Lead

PriceTech Ltd

Phone: +64 21 263 5379

Email: wei.ren@pricetech.co.nz

Address: Level 4, 50 Manners Street, Wellington, New Zealand

Hongjun Wang

Project Manager

Beijing ShenZhou Aerospace Software Technology Co., Ltd

Phone: +86 10 134 011 83030 Email: wanghongjun@bjsasc.com

Address: 28 Yongfeng Road Haidian, Beijing, China